Guide to the Robert Blanchon Papers and Collection MSS 220
Fales Library and Special Collections
- Series V: Media, 144254
  - Subseries B: Video - Originals, 160273
    - I Can't Live in a World Without Love, undated; ID: 220.0005; 160037 (Box 6, Media ID: 220.0005)
      Format: VHS
    - I Can't Live in a World Without Love (Robert Blanchon/Art Dept.), September 2, 1998; ID: 220.0006; 160038 (Box 6, Media ID: 220.0006)
    - I Can't Live in a World Without Love (Master), 1997; ID: 220.0007; 160039 (Box 6, Media ID: 220.0007)
      Format: DVD-R
    - I Can't Live in a World Without Love (Master, Non-Edit Format), 1997; ID: 220.0008; 160040 (Box 6, Media ID: 220.0008)
    - I Can't Live in a World Without Love (Robert Blanchon/Art Dept.; Master from VHS), September 2, 2009; ID: 220.0009; 160041 (Box 6, Media ID: 220.0009)
    - Legacy of Denial: a film by rob burkett and greg karout, 2005; ID: 220.0010; 160042 (Box 6, Media ID: 220.0010)
    - let's just kiss + say goodbye, 1995; ID: 220.0011; 160043 (Box 6, Media ID: 220.0011)
      Format: 3/4" Umatic
    - let's just kiss + say goodbye, undated; ID: 220.0013; 160044 (Box 6, Media ID: 220.0013)
    - let's just kiss + say goodbye, undated; ID: 220.0014; 160045 (Box 6, Media ID: 220.0014)
    - let's just kiss + say goodbye, undated; ID: 220.0015; 160046 (Box 6, Media ID: 220.0015)
    - let's just kiss + say goodbye (rough audio mix, for review only), undated; ID: 220.0016; 160047 (Box 6, Media ID: 220.0016)
      Duration: 00:08:56
    - let's just kiss + say goodbye (Jeanne Dunning's copy), undated; ID: 220.0017; 160048 (Box 6, Media ID: 220.0017)
    - let's just kiss + say goodbye (Master), undated; ID: 220.0018; 160049 (Box 6, Media ID: 220.0018)
    - let's just kiss + say goodbye, undated; ID: 220.0019; 160050 (Box 6, Media ID: 220.0019)
    - let's just kiss + say goodbye (Master Beta), undated; ID: 220.0020; 160051 (Box 6, Media ID: 220.0020)
    - let's just kiss + say goodbye (Master), undated; ID: 220.0021; 160053 (Box 6, Media ID: 220.0021)
    - let's just kiss + say goodbye (From Jeanne Dunning VHS Copy), undated; ID: 220.0022; 160054 (Box 6, Media ID: 220.0022)
    - Loved/Loop Tape (Master from VHS), undated; ID: 220.0023; 160052 (Box 6, Media ID: 220.0023)
    - Loved/Loop Tape, 1998; ID: 220.0024; 160055 (Box 6, Media ID: 220.0024)
    - Mourning (Tape 1 of 2): Griffith Park (2 takes), Observatory, Coral Sands, Sunset 8, September 16, 1996; ID: 220.0025; 160056 (Box 6, Media ID: 220.0025)
      Format: Hi8
    - Mourning (Tape 2 0f 2): Flex, Melrose Baths, Vortex, Hollywood Spa, Bedroom (5 takes), September 14, 1996; ID: 220.0026; 160061 (Box 6, Media ID: 220.0026)
    - Robert Blanchon (Copy from Kiss #1), Undefined; ID: 220.0012; 160429 (Box 6, Media ID: 220.0012)
    - Robert Blanchon/Untitled, undefined; ID: 220.0036; 160430 (Box 6, Media ID: 220.0036)
    - Robert Blanchon/Untitled, undefined; ID: 220.0037; 160432 (Box 6, Media ID: 220.0037)
    - Robert Blanchon/Untitled, Undefined; ID: 220.0038; 160433 (Box 6, Media ID: 220.0038)
    - Robert Blanchon Quicktime Files, undated; ID: 220.0039; 160072 (Box 6, Media ID: 220.0039)
    - Situations (unedited situations source, situations title (2 takes), I can't live in a world.. .titles (2 takes: white background), I can't live.. .titles (1 take: black background), I can't live.. .hair imagery (source), undated; ID: 220.0028; 160062 (Box 6, Media ID: 220.0028)
    - Situations I, II, III: edited excerpts (master copy), 1997; ID: 220.0029; 160063 (Box 18, Media ID: 220.0029)
    - Situations (rough cut), undated; ID: 220.0030; 160066 (Box 18, Media ID: 220.0030)
    - Situations (rough cut, not edited for installation), 1994; ID: 220.0031; 160067 (Box 18, Media ID: 220.0031)
    - Situations (scrap footage) preceded by When Women Loose Their Tales (movie taped from TV), February 11, 1996; ID: 220.0032; 160068 (Box 18, Media ID: 220.0032)
    - Situation I (office), 1994; ID: 220.0033; 160069 (Box 18, Media ID: 220.0033)
      Format: VHS-C
    - Situation (unedited), 1994; ID: 220.0034; 160070 (Box 18, Media ID: 220.0034)
    - Windscreen Cypress, undated; ID: 220.0035; 160071 (Box 18, Media ID: 220.0035)
  - Subseries C: Audio - Access Copies, 160274
    Access copies may not be currently available. Please contact a Fales archivist for access.
  - Subseries D: Audio - Originals, 160275
    - Natalie and Friends or cardio tape, ID: 220.0041; 161865 (Box 6, Media ID: 220.0041)
      Format: 1/4" audiocassette
      Duration: [00:90:00]
      Program content: unknown
    - Robert Blanchon in NC, 1998; ID: 220.0040; 160320 (Box 6, Media ID: 220.0040)
      Program content: Homemade mixed music tape
  - Subseries E: Vinyl Recordings, 160276
    - [Unidentified 7" record. Side A: Fireweed; Western Skies Side B: Willow Wept-N-Rise; Ohne Titel], 1977; 160321 (Box 18, Media data_value_missing_05241f58822a8133a0acf3398c2d4e34)
      Sound Disc: Analog, 45 rpm; 7 in.
    - I'm still in love with you, 1998; 160277 (Box 18, Media data_value_missing_eee8483fa66bba5d154cffafd08b5fe9)
      Sound Disc: Analog, 331/3 rpm; 12 in. with booklet
      Description: artists' and musicians' tribute to Al Green record. Blanchon's artwork is included in accompanying booklet.
- Series VI: Books, 144255
  Series VI: Print Material contains books owned by Robert Blanchon that arrived at Fales as part of the collection.
  - Holidays on Ice by David Sedaris, 1998; 156003 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Christian Boltanski: Lessons of Darkness, 1988; 156004 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Salton Sea Yesterday and Today by Mildred de Stanley, 1966; 156005 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - The Young Physique, Volume 6, Number 5, July-August 1965; 156006 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Funk & Wagnall's New Standard Encyclopedia of Universal Knowledge, 1931 (Box 60, Folder 2-8)
  - Sound and Hearing, 1968 (Box 60, Folder 1)
  - The Encyclopedia of Photography, 1975 (Box 60, Folder 9-13, Box 61, Folder 1-13)
- Series VIII: Memorial and Posthumous Files, 144257
  Series VIII: Memorial contains memorial-related planning materials gathered after Blanchon's death, including letters of condolence, a mailing list, slides of family and friends, and copies of Robert Blanchon obituaries.
  - An Illustrated Eulogy for Robert, Undated; 156051 (Box 9)
    Scope and Content
    An Illustrated Eulogy for Robert was created by two of Robert Blanchon's former students at the School of the Art Institute of Chicago.
  - John Neff "Untitled (Aroma/1981) Negatives, 2011; 215621 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    These negatives were created by artist John Neff from the Untitled (Aroma/1981) prints in the Blanchon Papers; he used the negatives to create new prints that were exhibited at the Golden Gallery in Chicago in 2011. The negatives were donated to Fales after the exhibition.
  - John Neff "Untitled (Aroma/1981) Negatives, 215622 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Memorial Planning Mailing List (Folder 1 of 2), 2003; 157475 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Memorial Planning Mailing List (Folder 2 of 2), 2003; 157478 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Memorial Related Ephemera: Condolences, 1999; 157479 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Memorial Related Ephemera: Personal Photographs, Slides, 2003; 157481 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Obituaries, Will, 1999-2000; 157498 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Untitled [Business Card - New York], 2009; 264060 (Box 9)
    Box of business cards based on Blanchon's circa 1990 work "Untiteld [Business Card - New York]", re-created for the 2009 exhibition of Blanchon's work held at the Fales Library & Special Collections in 2009.
  - Untitled [Business Card - Los Angeles], 2009; 264061 (Box 9)
    Box of business cards based on Blanchon's circa 1995 work "Untiteld [Business Card - Los Angeles]", re-created for the 2009 exhibition of Blanchon's work held at the Fales Library & Special Collections in 2009.
  - personal business card no. 3, circa 1995; 264062 (Box 9)
    Box of business cards based on Blanchon's circa 1995 work "personal business card no. 3", re-created for the 2009 exhibition of Blanchon's work held at the Fales Library & Special Collections in 2009.
- Series IX: Visual AIDS, 144258
  Series IX: Visual AIDS contains material generated by Visual AIDS during their production of the Robert Blanchon Catalog. It includes email correspondence, catalogs from Blanchon's exhibitions, copies of articles written about Blanchon and his artwork, contact information for collectors and gallerists, slides of Blanchon's work, grant proposals to fund the project, and the final catalog published in 2006, titled Robert Blanchon. The Visual AIDS materials also include correspondence, notes, plans for artworks, and publications created by Blanchon.
  - A Family Affair Atlanta College of Art Gallery, 2003; 157524 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Anonymous Museum, 2003; 157525 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Archives: Notes-Sasha Archibald, undated; 157526 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Archiving: Academic Records, 2003; 157527 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Archiving: Misc. Works on Paper, 2003; 157528 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Archiving: Promotional Copy, 1993-1994; 157529 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Archiving: Proposal Drafts, 2004; 157530 (Box 4, Folder 7, Box Shared Fales 016)
  - Artist Publication: Ten by Ten, 2000; 157531 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Artists Space, 2003; 157532 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - At the Mercy of Others: The Politics of Care Exhibition Catalog and Publicity Materials, Whitney Museum, 2005; 157533 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Blanchon Writings Collected By Visual AIDS, 1996-1998; 157534 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Blanchon Writings Collected by Visual Aids, 1995; 157535 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Collectors, 2004-2006; 157536 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Confirmed "Collection of", 2006; 157537 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence for Whitewalls Exhibition (Visual Aids Collected), 2003-2004; 157538 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Disappearing Act Bound and Unbound, 2003; 157539 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - The Drawing Center, 2003; 157540 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Email Correspondence: First Name A-E, 2003; 157541 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Email Correspondence: First Name F-J, 2003-2004; 157542 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Email Correspondence: First Name K-O, 2003-2004; 157543 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Email Correspondence: First Name P-T, 2003-2004; 157544 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Email Correspondence: U-Z, 2003; 157545 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Email Correspondence: Multiple Name, 2003; 157546 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Exhibition Catalogs, 2003; 157547 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Exhibition History: Correspondence, 2003; 157548 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Exhibition Resume, 2003; 157549 (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Exhibition Publication: Minimal Provocations, 2001; 157550 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Exhibition Publicity Materials: Blanchon + Andrew, 2006; 157551 (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Gallery 400, 2003; 157552 (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - Gallery M, 2003; 157566 (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Honcho Order Form-Visual Aids, 2004; 157567 (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - Images of Water: San Jose Museum of Art, 2003; 157569 (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - Ken Burkhart, 2005; 157570 (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - lalalalalalalala LACPS, 2003; 157571 (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - Loan Agreements, 2005-2006; 157572 (Box 4, Folder 35)
  - Looking for Work, 2004-2006; 157573 (Box 4, Folder 36)
  - M. Foxx Email Correspondence, 2003-2004; 157574 (Box 4, Folder 37)
  - Marc Foxx, 2005-2006; 157575 (Box 4, Folder 38)
  - MEC Email Correspondance, 2003-2004; 157576 (Box 4, Folder 39)
  - Minimal Provocations, Betty Rymer Gallery, 2000; 157583 (Box 4, Folder 40)
  - Modern Painters and Notes, 2003-2006; 157584 (Box 4, Folder 41)
  - Mourning After: Los Angeles Municiple Art Gallery, 2003; 157585 (Box 4, Folder 42)
  - N.A.M.E. Gallery, 2003; 157586 (Box 4, Folder 43)
  - Norton Foundation, 1990-2005; 157587 (Box 4, Folder 44)
  - Orange County Biennial, 2003; 157588 (Box 4, Folder 45)
  - Out Inside: Sesnon Gallery, 2003; 157589 (Box 4, Folder 46)
  - Pervert UCI, 2003; 157590 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Picture Show: Weinstein Gallery, 2003; 157591 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Plans, Mock-ups, Installation Instructions, 2006-2007; 157592 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Proposal Planning: Final Proposal, 2004; 157593 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Proposal Planning: Inventories, 2003; 157594 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Proposal Planning: Loan Agreements, Invoices, Consignments, 1991-1998; 157595 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Proposal/Planning: Notes/Meeting Agendas, 2004; 163096 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Proposal Planning: Proposal Email, Correspondance, 2004; 157596 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Randolph Street Gallery, 2003; 157597 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Robert Blanchon Catalogue/Visual Aids Publication, 2006; 157599 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Robert Blanchon Estate Project Statement, undated; 157600 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - The Robert Blanchon Estate Project Stationary, undated; 157601 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Robert Blanchon: Marc Foxx Gallery, 2003; 157602 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Robert Blanchon and MEC: Momenta Art Gallery, 2003; 157603 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Robert Blanchon: UNC Art Gallery, 157605 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Sad Songs Exhibition: Promotional and Administrative Materials, 2006; 157606 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Side Street Project, 2003; 157607 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Spaceship Earth/Art in General, 2003; 157608 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Terminals UCI 1996, 2003; 157609 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Vital Documents: Bibliography, 2004; 157610 (Box 5, Folder 20)
- Series VII: Objects, 144256
  Series VII: Objects contains objects either related to art production or objects which had personal significance. All objects belonged to Robert Blanchon.
  - Blanchon's Filofax diary, Undated; 156049 (Box 7, Object ID: 220.2.0064)
  - Glass shelf, Undated; 156050 (Box 25, Object ID: 220.2.0065)
  - Rolls of film stills from Blanchon's film Untitled [Situations], Undated; 156000 (Box 24, Object ID: 220.2.0066)
  - Beaded "R" and sun clothing patches, Undated; 155979 (Box 8, Object ID: 220.2.0042)
  - Borbro Superfine Epsom Salt, Undated; 155991 (Box 8, Object ID: 220.2.0054)
  - Brown cloth satchel with textile samples, Undated; 155984 (Box 7, Object ID: 220.2.0047)
  - Buttons shaped like chewing gum, 172210 (Box 8, Object ID: 220.2.0067)
  - Le Corbusier glass negatives (5 total), Undated; 155995 (Box 8, Object ID: 220.2.0058)
  - Eyeglass case, leather, 172211 (Box 8, Object ID: 220.2.0069)
  - Eyeglass case, orange needlepoint, 172212 (Box 8, Object ID: 220.2.0070)
  - Eyeglasses, blue frames, 172213 (Box 8, Object ID: 220.2.0071)
  - Eyeglasses, tortoiseshell, 172214 (Box 8, Object ID: 220.2.0072)
  - Framed photograph of dog with green outfit and hat, Undated; 155996 (Box 8, Object ID: 220.2.0059)
  - Framed photograph of a woman with a blue dress, Undated; 155997 (Box 8, Object ID: 220.2.0060)
  - Hankerchief with a stitched "R", Undated; 155985 (Box 8, Object ID: 220.2.0048)
  - ID tag: Art Institute of Chicago Faculty, 1998; 172217 (Box 8, Object ID: 220.2.0074)
  - ID tag: Art Institute of Chicago Faculty, 1999; 172218 (Box 9, Object ID: 220.2.0075)
  - Khaki-colored sun hat, Undated; 155983 (Box 7, Object ID: 220.2.0046)
  - Leather bound book with handmade paper, Undated; 155988 (Box 8, Object ID: 220.2.0051)
  - Leather case with green eyeglasses, Undated; 155987 (Box 8, Object ID: 220.2.0050)
  - Leather Ration book with postcards, Undated; 155978 (Box 8, Object ID: 220.2.0041)
  - MissOGYNY sash, Undated; 155982 (Box 7, Object ID: 220.2.0045)
  - "No it Can" palindromic work for two, Undated; 155977 (Box 8, Object ID: 220.2.0040)
  - Olene soap (one piece in a box), Undated; 155989 (Box 8, Object ID: 220.2.0052)
  - Piece of wood "you're in my world now, bitch", undated; 155980 (Box 8, Object ID: 220.2.0043)
  - Plastic bag of clothing labels, undated; 155976 (Box 8, Object ID: 220.2.0039)
  - Red plastic invitation to create a Christmas window for Barneys, undated; 155975 (Box 8, Object ID: 220.2.0038)
  - Red, yellow, blue, and burgundy bandanas, undated; 155981 (Box 7, Object ID: 220.2.0044)
    Description Bandanas were used in Blanchon's series of photographs of bandanas.
  - Sunglasses, yellow lenses, 172215 (Box 8, Object ID: 220.2.0073)
  - Sunglasses, pink frames, 172216 (Box 8, Object ID: 220.2.0068)
  - Small black frame with chicken feet, Undated; 155994 (Box 8, Object ID: 220.2.0057)
  - Small framed photograph of man (Robert Blanchon's brother John), Undated; 155993 (Box 8, Object ID: 220.2.0056)
  - Wonderful Charms cola candy, Undated; 155990 (Box 8, Object ID: 220.2.0053)
  - Wood carving with face, Undated; 155986 (Box 8, Object ID: 220.2.0049)
  - Box of family photographs, Undated; 155992 (Box 9, Object ID: 220.2.0055)
    Description: A box of family photos and snapshots arranged into categories with labelled tabs. Arrangement is assumed to have been Blanchon's.
    Photo Categories: family; friends; John; Todd; places; work; Bergman; Foxx; R. Kahn Pillow.
  - Polaroid 230 camera, Undated; 155999 (Box 9, Object ID: 220.2.0062)
  - SLR camera, Pentax Asahi 50mm lens, black leather case, Undated; 155998 (Box 9, Object ID: 220.2.0061)
  - Stamp: The Robert Blanchon Estate Project, Undated; 156001 (Box 9, Object ID: 220.2.0063)